All right, we'll get started. So, uh,
first just want to say really proud of
our process this off season. Uh, it
starts with our pro staff, um, which is
led by DJ Horde. Um, did a great job.
It's a lot of work through the fall
getting us prepared for for this time of
year. U, also want to give a a special
thanks to Matt Feinstein
who runs our cap and negotiations.
It's been awesome to see him grow and
develop. Uh we're fortunate to have him
and I know I couldn't do this uh without
him. Um and then lastly want to thank
our coaches. Uh anytime that you get
into postseason play, your window for
evaluations gets smaller and smaller. Um
we loaded those guys up pretty good. Uh
especially the defensive staff. Um and
they answer the bell which obviously
gives us a lot of clarity in terms of
what we need as a football team. Um and
it's our goal to to find that and help
them. I think there's a common theme uh
with the guys that we brought in. Uh
one, we wanted to get faster, more
explosive, and I think we did that. I
know we did that. We want guys that are
passionate about football, that play our
style and our brand of football, and I
know we did that. And then especially um
the leadership uh to continue to enhance
our roster so that we can continue to
push forward uh be a championship
caliber team. Um I know we got better
through through this phase. Um,
obviously there's a lot of things that
are are unexpected that happen in this
job. Um, Drew being one of them. Uh,
that retirement was a little bit of a
popup on us. Um, I want to respect him
and his decision. So, the why reasons
why and all that, I'll I'll let him
answer those things at at his time. Um,
but I'm proud of our organization for
adapting and adjusting. Um, which
allowed us to bring in uh Brad Barry
here to help us um solidify our
offensive line and continue to play. Um,
also tough decisions is when you got to
make those business decisions um and
make moves um like trading DJ. DJ's one
of my favorite players, will always be
one of my favorite players. Um, I knew
that that was going to be tough for our
organization. Uh, I've mentioned this
before. My son is a passionate fan of
the Chicago Bears. He was not very happy
with me at all. Um, I think it was cool
DJ sent him a video telling him not to
be mad at dad. It's is part of the
business. So, um, like I said, I
appreciate everything those guys that
aren't here uh did for our organization
to help us um, ascend and and get better
um, and get us on the doorstep of of
again being a championship caliber team.
But I'll answer open it up to any
questions.
>> Kevin B was the one guy that publicly
you said you'd like to have back and you
said that you'd talk.
>> Um why didn't that come to fruition and
and once you signed Kobe was a reunion
kind of out out the window or was there
a chance even the last day?
>> Yeah, that's what makes this part of
your difficult. Um you have certain
plans. there's guys that you would like
to have back and kind of seeing how the
landscape's going to, you know, set up
and you do your research.
When we watch Kobe's tape, um he was a
guy that got us excited because again,
he played our style of ball. He played
fast. He played physical. Um those are
the things that DA is looking for that
we're looking for. Um we thought there
was leadership there. he's young and um
you know we had to kind of adapt to to
that and we had an opportunity to bring
a really good player in and and that's
the decision that we made.
>> Ryan briefly about getting faster. How
important was it and big of a objective
to get faster on defense specifically?
>> Yeah, it's something I noticed we all
noticed I think especially in the the
postseason and really down the the last
part of the fall. Um, in order to play
the style we need to play, we need to be
able to close on the football a lot
faster than than what we have been
doing. Um, so that was the emphasis
going into it and again watching these
guys tape, we answered that.
>> Ryan, with the pass rush, um, to ask
this in a way that you are able to
answer it, a lot of bigname expensive
players were available to trade or free
agents.
>> What is the rationale that you had in
showing some restraint in that? Yeah,
again, I think I've mentioned this over
the years, constantly just looking at
short-term, long-term, uh, what's going
to help this football team now. Um, but
also being conscious of what's going to
happen down the road. U, we want to
sustain success. We've talked about that
a lot. In order to do that, we have to
be very calculated with the moves that
we make. Um so when we were looking
through different situations um we took
that into account and we felt like um
sticking with our plan and going into
free agency that was the best thing for
us to do.
>> More so more so about the um the draft
capital or the salary cap like how did
the two play together?
>> Those things definitely played a part.
>> Ryan with Drew with Drew how much back
and forth was there with him before his
eventual announcement?
>> Yeah, again I don't want to get too into
that. There's obviously that's a a big
personal decision. Um anytime a player
has, you know, dealing with certain
things and and they feel like the best
course of action is is to retire. Um
that's obviously a tough thing, but you
have to respect it. Um and that's what
we did. We respect his decision that was
best for him and um and then you just
adjust and you move.
>> Connected with that, the adjustment of
trying to find your next center. How did
you guys work through that process and
what ultimately led you to Garrett?
>> Yeah, really good process. We all got
together. Um, again, our coach has done
a fantastic job. We sat down with
uh with Ben, Dan, and Kyle and looked at
kind of the the landscape with the
center landscape. Um, we monitored a lot
of different things that were happening.
The big thing for us is finding the
right fit in terms of what's going to,
you know, be adaptable and and that's
going to fit into especially the outside
zone scheme, mid zone and
we kind of went through that list and
what's what's best for us. Um, you go to
the free agency, you can trade. Um, we
felt like the best thing for us to do,
uh, was to make that trade with a
veteran center that's played with a
young quarterback before that's very
good with his communication, smart, been
in different systems. We feel like he
can plug in and have command of that O
line.
>> Two years ago, you gave DJ the
extension. What happened in the two
years between then and now? Is it more
about the growth of the team around him
that made him expendable or was there
another reason?
>> Yeah. Um, you know, like I said, we're
always looking at there's a financial
piece of it. Um, but you're also looking
at the room and when you have Rome, um,
Roma Dun and how talented he is. I know
he went through some injuries last year.
You look at what, uh, Luther did. Um,
again, that's why you follow the draft
board. Um, I did not expect Luther
Birden to be where he was and he showed
up and and showed some big-time flashes.
Every time that dude touches the ball,
special things can happen. Um, and then
obviously our tight end um is a special
player as well. Um, so with that said,
you know, you have to look at different
moves that are going to help you
continue to build your football team,
and that's what we felt like was best.
>> In terms of the return for him, what was
what was the market like? Uh, and were
you obviously pretty pleased you were
able to get it, too?
>> Yeah. Um, there's quite a few teams that
were interested. Um, I I probably a
little bit different when it comes to
trades. Um, there's opportunity to put
DJ in a really cool spot for him to have
success. Unfortunately, we have to play
him um next year. But um I think for his
career, for that team, um I think it's a
like I I told one of my friends, I'm
from Western New York, and I said, "My
immediately my immediate family is not
very happy with me. My extended family
is very happy with me." So, um yeah, we
wish him well.
>> Ryan, the Crosby situation made waves
across the league this week. What was
your reaction to everything that
happened with that subject?
>> Yeah, I mean, it's the world we live in
right now where we jump to conclusions.
Um, I don't know what happened. I'm not
in that building. Um, so I just I let
those people worry about that. It's not
my problem. But, um, you know, this
job's hard. Uh, you never have black and
white. It's always gray when you're
making decisions. So, I'm sure there was
things that
they were working through that they had
to make that decision. But, um, again,
that's that's that's something they got
to worry about. I don't need to worry
about that right now. Ryan, did you have
much uh dialogue at all about Ian
Cunningham and the compensatory picks?
[snorts]
>> Yeah. Uh
[laughter]
I'll see most of you guys at the league
meetings and we can talk about that. Um
I'll leave that alone right now.
>> With with Kobe, when you when you
watched his tape, what were the things
that really popped to you that that fit?
>> Yeah, play style. Um he plays fast,
instincts, jump off tape. uh his ability
to anticipate. Um like I said before,
we're looking for guys that are
passionate about ball. You can see that
in his body language and how he moves.
Um anytime you bring a player in and
your phones go off, coach's front office
um on how pissed off Seattle was not
having him back, but also how fortunate
we are to have a guy like this in our
building. Um that's what you want to
hear. Um and that's exactly what
happened. So we're fired up. You know,
anytime you're in these positions, it's
crazy how fast time goes by because it
[snorts] wasn't that long ago draft
process. Um, he was a guy that you got
excited about. Jeff Shyver,
um, one of our our veteran scouts was on
the table doing jumping jacks for him
and he's excited to have him on the team
now. So, um, it's great.
>> You talking about, uh, speed, what, uh,
does having, uh, Devin at the linebacker
position add to the field? Um, you know,
a different element.
>> Yeah, just his ability to take the air
out. I mean, when he triggers, he goes,
um, another one, again, time goes by. I
remember watching him at Michigan. Um,
the play style, he plays fast. Uh, that
helps with with range and coverage. Um,
and again, if you think about DA's
system, it's a perfect perfect fit.
>> Right. How much did you guys actually
engage in Max Crosby talks? And will you
guys continue to monitor that situation?
uh you know, considering that it's still
sort of looming out there.
>> Yeah, I I've said before, we're always
going to monitor every situation. Um
sometimes it fits and and works with
what you got going on in terms of
resources. Sometimes it doesn't. Um
you know, we're involved. I mean, we
checked into it. We we looked to see if
it made sense, had some dialogue. Um
I'll just leave it at that. The last one
moves you made that offensive tackle
bringing back to back signing Jedric.
What's your vision going forward right
now for how you see that whole
competition playing?
>> Yeah. Um create competition. Um there's
kind of there's a lot going on at the
left tackle position. You got guys that
have played the position this this year
in terms of Theo Braxton that you know
had a crack at it early, was dealing
with some things. I'd like to see him
get back healthy uh to compete for that
spot. Um, and with Jedric, you know, if
you go back to early in his career
before the injury, um, playing at a
really high level, um, he's a guy that
we want, uh, Dan and Kyle to lean into.
I think we have phenomenal [snorts]
offensive line coaches. Uh, two really
good ones, um, that do a fantastic job
developing players. Um, so they're going
to lean into Jed to Jedric, spent time
with him. Um, we think there's a
connection there between our coaches and
him. He's willing to put in the work. Uh
we have an unbelievable performance
staff that's going to help him um get
his body right so he can compete at a
high level. And at the end of the day,
like any position, we want competition.
We want guys to rise to the level and
and at some point when we get to
September, someone's going to take that
job. And um and I'm excited to see how
that works